Guide to the Raul Salinas Papers, ca. 1950-1994
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3: Legal and Penal Activism
  - Leavenworth Prison Documents [255 Motion Roy Salinas] [1 of 4] n. d. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Leavenworth Prison Documents [255 Motion Roy Salinas] [2 of 4] n. d. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Leavenworth Prison Documents [255 Motion Roy Salinas] [3 of 4] n. d. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Leavenworth Prison Documents [255 Motion Roy Salinas] [4 of 4] n. d. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Misc. Legal n. d. (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - AZTLAN. Vol. 1, No 1. [2 copies] 1970 May 5 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - AZTLAN. Vol. 1, No 2. 1970 July 26 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - AZTLAN. Vol. 1, No 3. 1971 Mar. 9 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - AZTLAN. Vol. 1, No 4 1971 July 26 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - AZTLAN. Vol 2, No. 1 [2 copies] 197 Feb. 21 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - BUTTS, Leslie Ray [California State Prison- Soledad n. d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Entrelineas Proposal n. d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Leavenworth Prison Journals [1 of 3] 1970 -171 Jan. 29 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Leavenworth Prison Journals [2 of 3] 1971 Apr. 9 -1972 July (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Leavenworth Prison Journals [3 of 3] 1972 -1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Poems by Others n. d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - San Quentin Six n. d. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - To Salinas in Leavenworth for Oscar Collazo n. d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - SUNFIGHTER; Vol. 3, No. 1 1975 Mar. -Apri. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - VALDEZ, Luis and Stan STEINER, Aztlan. Alfred A. Knopf 1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Washington Prisons, 1 serial n. d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Attica-related reports [1 of 2] n. d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Attica-related reports [2 of 2] n. d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Prison Conditions- Reports and Publications [1 of 2] n. d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Prison Conditions- Reports and Publications [2 of 2] n. d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - C.O.R.A. (Leavenworth Penitentiary) 1967 -1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - News articles about Prison conditions and lawsuits n. d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Prison Activism n. d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Indian-Chicano Colation to Investigate Washington Prisons [1 of 3] 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Indian-Chicano Colation to Investigate Washington Prisons [2 of 3] 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Indian-Chicano Colation to Investigate Washington Prisons [3 of 3] 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Misc. notes on Prisons 1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Series 4: Public Appearances, 1972-1994
  - Academic Records [1 of 2] (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Academic Records [2 of 2] (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia, n.d. [includes passport, social security card] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings. 1967-1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings: SalinasÕ Prison Experience, 1971-1974. n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Viaje/Trip. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - El Centro de la Raza. 1973 April (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Seattle Thrid-Word Coalition. Seattle Youth Rights Coalition. c. 1973 Sept. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings. 1973-1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - El Sol de Santa Clara Writers Conference. 1974 May 24-26 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lectures & Presentations. 1974-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Sunfighter, Vol. 3, no. 1 (Mar.-Apr. 1975). 1975 Mar. -Apr. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - No Separate Peace, Vol. 1, no. 2 (June 20, 1975). 1975 Jun. 20 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Cuba: Venceremos Brigade. 1975-1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Calendars & Appointment Books. 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - University of Washington: teaching position. 1979 Autumn (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Tin-Tan Pocho Che Book Party Invitations, San Francisco. 1980 May 2 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Calendars & Appointment Books. 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Chicano/Latino Image in Cinema, University of Texas Center for Mexican-American studies. 1981 Autumn (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Kanto al Pueblo V. 1982 Aug. 21-28 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Curriculum Vitae, Raul Salinas. c. 1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - One More Canto. Joint Reading of Chicano & Native American Poets. Sacramento, CA. 1983 May 13 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - El Aviso, Vol. 2, no. 4 (Aug. 20 - Sept. 20, 1983). 1983 Aug. 20 -Sept. 20 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Salinas Activities. 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cuba Activities; misc. c. 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Media, 1987-1988 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Big Mountain Support Group Newsletter, Issue no. 2 (Autumn, 1987). 1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Travel Itineraries. 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Calendar & Appointment books. 1988 -n.d. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Presbyterian Criminal Justice Conference, Tampa, FL. 1989 Feb. 2 -5. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Film Proposal. 1989 Fall. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - National Movement of La Raza. 1993 Feb. 23 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - University of Texas, Informal Classes, Overview of Chicano & Native American Poetry. 1993 Spring (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - San Antonio Inter-American Bookfair & Literary Festival. 1993 Oct. 8 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Raul Salinas Archives. 1994 Jan. -July (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - City of Austin, Charter Review Committee Update. [1 of 2] 1994 Jan. 19 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - City of Austin. Charter Review Committee Update. [2 of 2] 1994 Jan. 19 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Native American Activities. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Writing on the Wall. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Austin Anthology. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Dobie Paisano Application. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Third World Communications. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Educational Presentations; youth. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - JailnÕ in Texas: The Artistic & Folkloric Perspective. 13-14 July [n.y.] (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Task Force on Hispanic American Arts: Symposium on the Hispanic American Aesthetics 28 April [n.y.] (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Festival del Sexto Sol, San Francisco. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Misc. Activities, n.d. [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Activities, n.d. [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Activities, n.d. [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Fliers & Announcements, 1974 Jan. 25 - 1983 May 4. 1974 Jan. 25 -1983 May 4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Fliers & Announcements, 1983 May 13 - 1988 May 2. 1983 May 13 -1988 May 2. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fliers & Announcements, 1989 May 23 - 1993 Mar. 18; n.d. 1989 May 23 -1993 Mar. 18; n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Fliers & Announcements, n.d. [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fliers & Announcements, n.d. [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Broadsides, 1981-1982; n.d. n.d. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Leaflets. n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Series 5: Photographs
  - CRAIGIE, Lois. [Austin American Statesmen] n. d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Mendoza, Steve. Nuevo Leon Restaurant; Austin, TX [sub: Dan and Nancy Lusher] 1988 Sept. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - SALINAS, Raul. Free Peltier Rally, Seattle, WA 1977 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - SALINAS, Raul. Geneva and Lybia [1 of 3] 1987 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - SALINAS, Raul. Geneva and Lybia [2 of 3] 1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - SALINAS, Raul. Geneva and Lybia [3 of 3] 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - SALINAS, Raul. Leonard State Trial; Milwaukee, Wisconsin 1978 Jan. -Feb. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - SALINAS, Raul. LPDC - Marion AIM Conference- Minn. 1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - AIM Conference; Minneapolis, MN (LPDC) 1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - ALLEN, E. - S.A.L.A. press conference; SHIA Trail of Self Determination 1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Arte/Murales n. d. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Austin 1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Austin: Raul - early fotos n. d. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Cascadia Takeover- Tacoma WA 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Cascadia Takeover 1976, John Trudellis Visit, 1977 n.d. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Cincinnati, Ohio Trail 1976 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Cuba 1975. 1977, 1982 [ 1 of 3] n. d. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Cuba 1975. 1977, 1982 [2 of 3] n. d. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Cuba 1975. 1977, 1982 [2 of 3] n. d. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Cuba 1975. 1977, 1982 [3of 3] n. d. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - FELS, Robert / SANCHY, Fred. LPDC- Longest Walk, Amsterdam Vancouver, Milwaukee 1977 -1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Geneva 1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Geneva 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Homies" (Zapata, Edward; Moveno, Robert; etc.) 1958 n. d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - I. I. T. C.- Geneva 1981, 1987; Nicaragua 1987 (International Treaty Council) n. d. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - International Treaty Conference, I. I. T. C. White Earth, MN n. d. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Jesus Trevino Presentation: Chiacnos in the Media Class; UT Austin 1985 Spring (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Kentucky Trail 1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Leavenworth/ Marian Album [1 of 2] n. d. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Leavenworth/ Marian Album [2 of 2] n. d. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Los Ninos n. d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - LPDC - Ogalla, etc. 1981 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - LPSG/Seattle 1977 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - LPSG/Austin n. d. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - LPSG, Austin n. d. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Lydia, Mendoza, Pan Au Center n. d. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Morals and Indian Solidarity Rally, San Francisco 1977 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - NICA Rally- Austin n. d. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Northwest 1972 -1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Northwest Indies n. d. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Peltier Trial, 1978. Peterson, Tom: LPDC- St. Louis, 1985 n. d. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Philadelphia, PA Trail 1976 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Pittsburgh, PA (Harrisburg) Trail 1976 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Pluto Art Show, San Antonio 1985 Jan. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Poetas n. d. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Prison- Leavenworth, Marion, Hunstville [1 of 2] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Prison- Leavenworth, Marion, Hunstville [2 of 2] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rican Morals: N. Mexico familia, AIM Conference: MPLs, MN, etc. n. d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Q House, SamÕs Grocery Graffitti Project n. d. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - S.A.Y.S. - the boys- n. d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - S.A.Y.S. - the boys- Jeanette/Adela n. d. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - S.A.Y.S. Outing- Lakeway Marina 1988 Sept. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Scottshluff Nebraskas Trail 1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Seattle/ Raza [1 of 5] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Seattle/ Raza [2 of 5] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Seattle/ Raza [3 of 5] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Seattle/ Raza [4 of 5] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Seattle/ Raza [5 of 5] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Shia; Clift, State Park Trail 1976 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - South Austin Youth Services, Da Boys 1986 -1989 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Teatro del Projo, University of Washington, Seattle 1973 -1975 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Trail 1976 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - University of Texas Media [1 of 2] [Rainey St. UT Media Files] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - University of Texas Media [2 of 2] [Rainey St. UT Media Files] n. d. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Washington/ Indios- FrankÕs Landing, Sid MillÕs Family 1976 Nov. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Wounded Knee 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Wyoming Trail, Ft. Laramie 1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Yellow Thunder Camp, South Dakota n.d. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Youth Work n.d. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified photographs n.d. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified photographs n.d. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified slides n.d. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Photo Album [Leavenworth ?] [1 of 5] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Photo Album [Leavenworth ?] [2 of 5] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified Photo Album [Leavenworth ?] [3 of 5] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Photo Album [Leavenworth ?] [4 of 5] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified Photo Album [Leavenworth ?] [5 of 5] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified [photograph of Salinas and young lady] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Untitled Prison Album [1 of 3] [photocopies of album] n.d. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Untitled Prison Album [2 of 3] n. d. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Untitled Prison Album [3 of 3] n. d. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Untitled Photo Album [1 of 4] n. d. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Untitled Photo Album [2 of 4] n. d. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Untitled Photo Album [3 of 4] n. d. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Untitled Photo Album [4 of 4] n. d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Series 6: Audiovisual Materials
  - a. Primary Materials
    - Steve Robideau & Raul Salinas. Conferences in San German, Puerto Rico. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      1 sound cassette (90 min. )
    - Raul Salinas. Awareness Week, WSU, 1981 Apr. 20 1981 April 20 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      1 sound cassette (90 min.)
    - Geneva Rap #2. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - American Writers Congress. New York City, NY. Federal Control of Information 1 and 2. 1981 Oct. 9-12 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      1 sound cassette.
    - Festival Floricanto I. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
      1 sound cassette (120 min.)
    - Cuba n.d. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Raul Salinas. Report on Geneva Conference. Stevie Wonder. Talking Book. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 7)
      1 sound cassette (60 min.)
    - Raul Salinas. Interview with Lorin Cuoco. St. Louis, Mo. 1987 May 18 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Cuba. Chile Spring 1975 Delegation. 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Dark Waters. Mona Lisa. Bill Lyttle. Raul Salinas. Michael McClellan. David Press. Wake up in the Morning. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Cuba. FMCN n.d. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Orientation -- Cuba. Chilean Delegation. Cuba 1975. 1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Jose Montoya. Estaban Villa. El Centro de la Raza. Seattle, 1979. 1979 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Steve Robideau & Raul Salinas in Conferences in San German, Puerto Rico. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - FMLN/FDR Reps. Cuba. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - International Indian Tready Council. Delegates met with Ernesto Cardenal. Managua, Nicarauga. 1981 Dec. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - JailinÕ in Texas. RaulÕs presentation, Austin 198. Lagua Gloria Museum. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)
      1 sound cassette (120 m in.)
    - Presentation on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination. Presentation on the Elimination of Racial and Economic Discrimination. n.d. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Che/ Camilo Interview n.d. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified Videocassette. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      1 videocassette.
    - Mis Amigos. Interviews with NilakButler. Produced y S. Stewart. 1984 Sept. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Teatro Vivo" y Domingo IXCOY. Produced by Sol Rojo Media. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Radio KCOR, San Antonio, Texas. Survival of American Indians Interview. 1975 Sept. 17 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      1 reel.
    - Chicano Poetry. Raul Salinas & Ernesto Maldonado reading their own works in Spanish & English. Ethnic Cultural Center, University of Washington, Seattle. 1972 May [?] (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Raul Salinas. Un Trip through the Mind Jail, 1973. Chicano Poetry #2. 1973 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Raul Salinas. Poem Take II & Interview. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 7)
      1 vidocassette.
    - Raul Salinas. Poetry at Union. 1980 Mar. 29 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Uncommon Kin. "Raul Salinas." Carver Library. n.d. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Mis Amigos II. 10th International Indian Treaty. Council with Mausha Gomez & Raul Salinas. S. Stewart. 1984 Oct. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Mis Amigos II. Raul Salinas. International Indian Treaty Council. 1984 Sept. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Raul Salinas: Festival Estudiantil workshop at Webb School. 1985 April 19 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Raul Salinas, "Uncommon Kin." #2 n.d. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Interview with Raul Salinas. n.d. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Guadalupe Cultural Art Center. Writing on the Wall/ Pinto Art Show. #3. n.d. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Guadalupe Cultural Art Center. Writing on the Wall/ Pinto Art Show. #2. n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Seventh International Indian Treaty Conference. Interview with Raul Salinas. n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Guadalupe Cultural Art Center. Writing on the Wall/Pinto Art Show. #5 n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Guadalupe Cultural Art Center. Writing on the Wall/Pinto Art Show. #4 n.d. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Raul Salinas remembers East Austin. #3. 1985 April 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Raul Salinas. Journey II. PSA for Mis Amigos. n.d. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Raul Salinas. Pinto ARt Show, Guadalupe Cultural Center. San Antonio, Texas. 1985 Jan. 25 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Interview with Raul Salinas, on "Puesto del Sol." 1979 Sept. 18 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Raul Salinas. Remembers East Austin. #1. 1985 April 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Raul Salinas Remembers East Austin. #2. 1985 April 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Raul Salinas. Journey II. n.d. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - b. Secondary Materials
    - Jesus Trevino. Bookstore, Pan-American Rec Shots [?] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Jesus Trevino. MAS Center Lounge. 1985 May 3 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - The Cultural Warriors. Presented by the American Institute for Learning. n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Mis Amigos. Dub of Russ Edit. Ruby Nelda [?] and Jose Flores [?] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Roberto Vargas. Poetry Reading. University of Washington, 197--. "13 Cantos to Gringo Landia" with Latin percussion accompaniment. 197-- (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Jose Angel giving lecture to Denver group. 9:00-12:00. Reel I. 1973 May 7 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Jesus Trevino. MAS Center Lounge, Universityof Texas. 1985 [?] May 7 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Jesus Trevino Bookstore. n.d. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Ruby Nelda y Jose Flores. #2. n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Mis Amigos II. Interview #2. With Bill Means, II TC. Ruby Nelda and Joes Flores. Visuals. n.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Raul Salinas. Resistencia Bookstore: Poetry Reading. Part II. n.d. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Ruby Nelda with Jose Flores. #3. Mis Amigos: Interview with Paul Hernandez on Nueva Vida I. 1984 July 31 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Uncomman [sic.] Kin. Akwesi Evans in Studio. n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Resistencia Bookstore: Poetry. Part 1. Raul Salinas. n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Los Chicanos de Seattle. Aired KOMO-TV 1973 Mar. 8 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Mis Amigos II. Interview with Bill Means, II TC. Jose Flores & Ruby Nelda Renez n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Series 7: Resistencia Bookstore and Red Salmon Press
  - Relampago Books. c. 1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Resistencia Bookstore Mail-outs. c. 1984 Jan. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Red Salmon Review. c. 1984 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Red Salmon / Resistence Public Service Announcements. 1985 April 24 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings. 1986-1993 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - WritersÕ Development Program. 1986 April -June (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Resistencia on the Move Benefit. c. 1987 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Articles. 1988 Nov. -Dec.; 1991 March 15-31. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Newpaper Articles. 1991 Jun. 21 -1992 July 3 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Canto Libre at Red Salmon Press. 1991 July 11 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Fliers. 1982 July 3 -1986 May 19 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Fliers. 1987 May 13 -1992 July 30 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Fliers. 1992 Aug. 27 -1994 Jun. 9; n.d. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Fliers, n.d. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Red Salmon & Resistencia Bookstore. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - The Assassination of Manuel Medina, TMs., n.d. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Red Salmon/Resistencia Statement of Purpose, n.d. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Notes on Red Salmon Review, No. 1, n.d. N.d. (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Series 8: Secondary Literature on Raul Salinas
  - Artwork, n.d. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - The Austin Light, Vol. 2, no. 25 (1981 Aug 20). 1981 Aug 20 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - The Austin Light, Vol. 8, no. 40 (1988 Dec. 23 - Jan. 5). 1988 Dec. 23 -Jan. 5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - The Austin Light, Vol. 2, no. 25 (1989 June 21-27). Includes "PoetÕs Night." 1989 June 21-27 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - El Aviso, Vol. 2, no. 3. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography. [Includes Table of Contents for The Pawn Review, Vol. 7, no. 3; introduction to work of Salinas by T. Ybarra-Frausto.] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Black Pride, Vol. 1, no. 31. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Breaking MenÕs Minds, n.d. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Cambon, Glauco. "Raul Salinas: Una Nueva Voz de la Poesia Americana," TMs., 8 pp., 1971 June. 1971 June (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Cambon, Glauco. "Raul Salinas: Una Nueva Voz de la Poesia Americana," Estratto da Annali di CaÕFoscari, Vol. 10. 1971 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Cisneros, Sandra. "Los Tejanos: A Testimony of the Silenced," Texas Humanist (1984 Nov. - Dec.). 1984 Nov. -Dec. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Cohen, Ben. "Austin poets share ÔintimaciesÕ," The Daily Texan, 1988 Oct. 17. 1988 Oct. 17 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Con Sandio, No. 24. [Includes "Facing Somoza"] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Dark Waters, Vol. 1, nos. 3 & 4. [Includes "The Jewel Thing."] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - The Echo. Columns for ÔQuartered Notes" by Raul Salinas. c. 1964 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Ericson, Davis Hanson. "Prison Literature and the Question of Genre: The Case of Raul Salinas," diss. University of Texas at Austin, 1989 Dec. 1989 Dec. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Ericson, David. "Writing and Reading Strategies in Pinto Poetry," 1988 Dec. 8. 1988 Dec. 8 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Ethnic Anthology, 1975. 1975 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Garcia-Giron, Edmundo. "The Chicanos: An Overview," n.d. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Gonzales, Ray. "The Well-Versed Movimiento," The Nation, 1994 Jan. 31. 1994 Jan. 31 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Grajeda, Rafael. "The Pachuco in Chicano Poetry: The Process of Legend-Creation," n.d. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Herndon, John. "Intimacies of the Ear," n.d. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Ibargoyen, Saul and Jorge Bocanera. Poesia Rebelde. Editores Mexicanos Unidos, 1978. 1978 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Journal of Emerging Raza Philosophies, Vol. 1, no. 4. n.d. (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Limited Edition, "Resenas: Prison, Poetry & Liberation," 1981 1981 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Metamorfosis, Vol. 2, nos. 1 & 2. [Includes "Short Eyes" by Raul Salinas and Yvonne Yarbo-Bejarano.] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Mission Cultural Center. c. 1980 May (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Murley, James Rudy. "Criticism of Salinas Poems by Murley," 1963 Oct. 1963 Oct. (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Novoa, John Bruce. "Literatura Chicana: La Respuesta al Caos," Revista de la Univ. de Mexico," Vol. 20, no. 24 (1975 Aug.). 1975 Aug. (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Olguin, Ben V. "Genealogy of th Pachuco as a Cultural Icon," 1993 Nov. 4. 1993 Nov. 4 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Olguin, Ben V. "Testimonios Pintos," diss. Stanford University, 1993. 1993 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - La Pena, Vol. 6, no. 3 (1991 Jul. -Aug.). [Includes "Poemas de Raul Salinas.] 1991 Jul. -Aug. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - La Pena, Vol. 7, no. 1 (1992 Feb. - Mar.) 1992 Feb. -Mar. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Poems about Raul Salinas: "A Raul Salinas Reader," n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Poetry. "Unity Vision," "Tres Poems," and others. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Public Television of Austin, Texas. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Randall, Margaret. "For La Vida Poesia: Los Chicanos," Revolucion y Cultura, No. 78 (Feb. 1979). 1979 Feb. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Rayas: Newsletter of Chicano Arts & Literature, No. 1 (1978 Jan. - Feb.) 1978 Jan. -Feb. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - The Reader: El Mero-Mero! n.d. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Reece, Ray,. "Busting out of the Mind Jail: Raul Salinas and his Poetry," n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Rescuing the World Center. Raul Salinas: "A Trip through the Mind Jail." n.d. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Revista Rio Bravo. "Poesia Chicana: Excerpts from A Trip through the Mind Jail." n.d. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Rivercity Review, Vol. 2, no. 2 (1988 Oct.) 1988 Oct. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Roderick, Rick. Rev. of Un Trip through the Mind Jail y Otras Excursions, n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Salinas, Raul R. Biographical Sketch. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Salinas, Raul R. Curriculum Vitae. c. 1982 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Salinas, Raul R. "Gloriana"; newspaper clipping, Daily Texan (1974 July 8). 1974 July 8 (Box 27, Folder 16)